Haibao Yu

PhD Student, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong

Email: yuhaibao94@gmail.com — Phone: +86-130-2110-1122 — Google Scholar — LinkedIn

Short Biography

I am a second-year Ph.D. student at MMLAB, **The University of Hong Kong**, advised by Professor Ping Luo. Additionally, I lead a research team focused on cooperative autonomous driving at the **Joint Research Center of Baidu and Tsinghua University**, collaborating closely with Professor Zaiqing Nie. Previously, I worked as a computer vision researcher for autonomous driving at **SenseTime Research**. My research encompasses 3D Perception, Motion Forecasting, End-to-End Autonomous Driving, V2X, and Efficient AI. Moreover, I led the development and release of several datasets for autonomous driving, including the pioneering real-world V2X dataset DAIR-V2X. Furthermore, I played a key role in establishing a deep learning model compression and deployment platform for autonomous driving research and mass production. Now, my research interests focus on developing Generative AI for autonomous driving and embodied AI.

EDUCATION AND VISITING

The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, ChinaSeptember 2022 — PresentPh.D. Student - Computer ScienceAdvisory: Professor Ping Luo

Research Topics: Autonomous Driving, V2X, Generative AI

Beihang University, Beijing, China

Master - Mathematics and Computational Mathematics

September 2016 — June 2019

Advisory: Professor Zhikun She

Master - Mathematics and Computational Mathematics
Research Topics: Control System, Differential Equation

Advisory

Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong, ChinaJuly 2016 — August 2016Visiting Student - High-performance ComputingAdvisory: Professor Xiaowen Chu

Sun Yat-Sen University, Guangzhou, China September 2012 — June 2016

Bachelor - Mathematics and Applied Mathematics

PUBLICATIONS

Topic: 3D Object Detection

- Haibao Yu, Yizhen Luo, et al. "DAIR-V2X: A Large-Scale Dataset for Vehicle-Infrastructure Cooperative 3D Object Detection". The IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition 2022 (CVPR2022)
- Haibao Yu, Yingjuan Tang, Enze Xie, Jilei Mao, Ping Luo, Zaiqing Nie. "Flow-Based Feature Fusion for Vehicle-Infrastructure Cooperative 3D Object Detection". Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 36 (NeurIPS2023)
- Ruiyang Hao*, Siqi Fan*, Yingru Dai, Zhenlin Zhang, Chenxi Li, Yuntian Wang, **Haibao Yu**, et al. "Roooper: A Real-World Large-Scale Dataset for Roadside Cooperative Perception". The IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition 2024 (CVPR2024)
- Siqi Fan, **Haibao Yu**, Wenxian Yang, Jirui Yuan, Zaiqing Nie. "Quest: Query Stream for Vehicle-Infrastructure Cooperative Perception". 2024 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automatio (**ICRA2024**)

Topic: Sequential Perception and Motion Prediction

- Haibao Yu, Wenxian Yang, et al. "V2X-Seq: A Large-Scale Sequential Dataset for Vehicle-Infrastructure Cooperative Perception and Forecasting". The IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition 2023 (CVPR2023)
- Hongzhi Ruan, **Haibao Yu**, Wenxian Yang, Siqi Fan, Yingjuan Tang, Zaiqing Nie. "Learning Cooperative Trajectory Representations for Motion Forecasting". (Arxiv/ECCV Submission, 2024)

Topic: End-to-End Autonomous Driving

• Haibao Yu, Wenxian Yang, Jiaru Zhong, Zhenwei Yang, Siqi Fan, Ping Luo, Zaiqing Nie. "End-to-End Autonomous Driving through V2X Cooperation". (Arxiv/ECCV Submission, 2024)

Topic: Efficient Artificial Intelligence

^{*} denotes equal contribution.

- Haibao Yu*, Qi Han*, Jianbo Li, Jianping Shi, Guangliang Cheng, Bin Fan. "Search What You Want: Barrier Penalty NAS for Mixed Precision Quantization". 16th European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV2020)
- Haibao Yu, Tuopu Wen, Guangliang Cheng, Jiankai Sun, Qi Han, Jianping Shi. "Low-bit Quantization Needs Good Distribution". The IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition Workshops (CVPRW2020)
- Tao Yang, Zhezhi He, Tengchuan Kou, Qingzheng Li, Qi Han, **Haibao Yu**, Fangxin Liu, Yun Liang, Li Jiang. "A Winograd-based CNN Accelerator with A Fine-grained Regular Sparsity Pattern and Mixed Precision Quantization". ACM Transactions on Reconfigurable Technology and Systems (TRETS, 2021)

Topic: Embodied AI

• Yao Mu, Junting Chen, Qinglong Zhang, Shoufa Chen, Qiaojun Yu, Chongjian Ge, Runjian Chen, Zhixuan Liang, Mengkang Hu, Chaofan Tao, Peize Sun, **Haibao Yu**, et al. "RoboCodeX: Multimodal Code Generation for Robotic Behavior Synthesis". International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML2024)

WORK EXPERIENCES: FULL TIME/PART TIME

Institute of AI Industry Research (AIR), Tsinghua University

Beijing, China

I am working at the AIR & Baidu Joint Research Lab and collaborate closely with Professor Zaiqing Nie. I lead a research team comprising 5-10 engineers and interns, focused on autonomous driving and cooperative autonomous driving.

• Part Time: Research Assistant/Intern

September 2022 — Present

• Full Time: Research Engineer

 $May\ 2021 - August\ 2022$

Department of Autonomous Driving, SenseTime

Beijing, China

I worked closely with Dr. Jianping Shi and Dr. Guangliang Cheng. I led an R&D team focused on deep learning model compression and deployment for autonomous driving, and participated in several mass production projects.

• Full Time: Computer Vision Researcher

April 2019 — May 2021

• Part Time: Computer Vision Research Intern

March 2018 — March 2019

HONORS and **AWARDS**

• Research Innovation Award, SenseTime (20 applied, only 3 were awarded.)	2020
• National Scholarship, Beihang University	2018
• President's Scholarship, Beihang University	2017
• Innovation and Entrepreneurship Scholarship, Ministry of Industry and Information Technology	2017
• 4th place winner of JD X Robot Challenge, Jingdong (prize: 20,000 RMB)	2017
• National Encouragement Scholarship, Sun Yat-sen University	2014

ACADEMIC SERVICES

- Academic Activities:
 - Primary Organizer of Workshop on Cooperative Intelligence for Autonomous Driving and Robotics, ECCV2024
 - Program Committe of Wearable Intelligence for Healthcare Robotics Workshop, ICRA2024
- Conference Review:
 - CVPR(2023, 2024), ICCV(2023), ECCV(2022, 2024)
- Journal Review:
 - IEEE Internet of Things Journal
 - IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology